<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Douglas Tofoli</title>
    <link>https://douglastofoli.dev/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Douglas Tofoli</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 21:17:06 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://douglastofoli.dev/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Your terminal with Oh My Zsh, Spaceship, Dracula and more functionalities</title>
      <link>https://douglastofoli.dev/en/posts/custom-terminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 21:17:06 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://douglastofoli.dev/en/posts/custom-terminal/</guid>
      <description>Letting your terminal better to work Hello there. Let&amp;rsquo;s configuration a beauty and productive terminal. This is not a detailed tutorial. I will leave here links and some commands on how I set up my terminal. It&amp;rsquo;s easy, just follow in order
Terminator Step by step 1. Install Zsh You need to install a different shell. But calm. Nothing will change in relation to bash
Access this page. This will help you with installation for your Linux distro.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Music] Enjoy the last working day of the week</title>
      <link>https://douglastofoli.dev/en/posts/its-friday-02-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 21:12:32 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://douglastofoli.dev/en/posts/its-friday-02-04/</guid>
      <description>Hi there!
Today I didn&amp;rsquo;t work on any personal projects. The day was full.
There are days when we need to stop, open a beer and relax. I recommend that you to do this.
Enjoy a song that a frien sent me some days ago. I loved and I want to share with you.
Have a good night and a great weekend! See you monday!
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting New Project [Planning]</title>
      <link>https://douglastofoli.dev/en/posts/starting-new-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 20:31:16 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://douglastofoli.dev/en/posts/starting-new-project/</guid>
      <description>The Planning: I started a new project. Unnamed yet, but I already know about what will be. It looks a bit silly but I want to do a money manager. An application that you can add entries for expenses and incomes.
How I started? Planning! I am planning the database. I intend to use PostgreSQL for my database.
I am using dbdiagram.io to create my schemas
dbdiagram.io On the left side I wrote in code what I want to represent in my tables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keychron Linux Function Keys</title>
      <link>https://douglastofoli.dev/en/posts/keychron-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 22:32:24 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://douglastofoli.dev/en/posts/keychron-linux/</guid>
      <description>When I bought a Keychron K2 I knew it would work in Windows and Mac, but I use Linux. But it’s just a keyboard… it should work.
Well&amp;hellip; It works! But on my OS Arch Linux with Gnome had a little problem. The FN keys didn’t work perfectly. Actually the FN keys were for MacOS, not Windows.
How I fixed:
 Use the switch on side of keyboard to change to Windows mode Hold Fn + X + L for 4 seconds to set the key row to Function mode  Type in the terminal:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World!</title>
      <link>https://douglastofoli.dev/en/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 22:07:05 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://douglastofoli.dev/en/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Hello, friend. How are you? I&amp;rsquo;m fine and I expect that you are fine too.
So&amp;hellip; this is my blog! 🎉🎉🎉
Yep! You are in it.
I hope that you will have good moments and nice readings here.
About what I&amp;rsquo;ll write? Hmmm&amp;hellip; about everything, I think. You can hope to find subjects about technologies, histories from how I learn something. Example: sometimes I have a trouble in my Linux and I search all over the internet to find a solution.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
