<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Douglas Tofoli</title>
    <link>https://douglastofoli.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Douglas Tofoli</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 18:04:05 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://douglastofoli.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Automating CRUD Operations with Macros in Elixir</title>
      <link>https://douglastofoli.dev/posts/automating-crud-operations-with-macros-in-elixir/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 18:04:05 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://douglastofoli.dev/posts/automating-crud-operations-with-macros-in-elixir/</guid>
      <description>When dealing with databases and information management systems, it is common to create CRUD (Create, Read, Update, Delete) operations in programming. However, Elixir, a robust and highly concurrent functional programming language, offers a powerful feature that can significantly simplify the process of creating CRUDs. In this article, I will share my experience in creating generalized CRUDs using Elixir macros.
Understanding Macros In Elixir, macros are special constructs that allow code generation at compile-time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How My XMonad Works</title>
      <link>https://douglastofoli.dev/posts/how-my-xmonad-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 11:27:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://douglastofoli.dev/posts/how-my-xmonad-works/</guid>
      <description>XMonad Configuration This is my personal configuration file for XMonad, a tiling window manager for X11. This configuration is highly customized and may not suit your needs out of the box, but you are welcome to use it as a starting point for your own configuration.
Table of Contents Dependencies Installation Customization Variables Navigation Workspaces Startup Layout Keybindings Dependencies Before you can use this configuration, you will need to install the following dependencies:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mechanical March Challenge: Learning Golang with the Help of a Nix Flake</title>
      <link>https://douglastofoli.dev/posts/exercism-and-the-mechanical-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 15:15:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://douglastofoli.dev/posts/exercism-and-the-mechanical-march/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a way to challenge yourself and improve your programming skills, the Exercism Mechanical March challenge is a great opportunity. This month, I decided to take on the challenge and tackle the Golang track.
To make the process smoother and more efficient, I prepared a Nix flake that would help me in the development of the exercises. If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar with Nix, it&amp;rsquo;s a package manager that allows for deterministic builds and is particularly helpful when working with multiple dependencies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Nix for Productivity</title>
      <link>https://douglastofoli.dev/posts/using-nix-for-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 14:30:10 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://douglastofoli.dev/posts/using-nix-for-productivity/</guid>
      <description>I love automations, and set up environments to development is very stressfull. Since I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Nix I&amp;rsquo;ve been had less work to configure my packages and my configurations.
And make your environment productivy is really easy. In some steps.
You need to have the package manager Nix installed on your system. Also need direnv, for integration, that enables automations.
Install Nix in whatever Linux distribution is simple, just run the installer:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://douglastofoli.dev/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 17:57:02 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://douglastofoli.dev/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello, my name is Douglas, and I am a passionate technology and programming student. Currently, I am studying Software Engineering and have professional experience in languages such as Typescript, PHP, and Elixir.
My programming journey began a few years ago when I decided to dive into the world of technology and learn how to create solutions for complex problems using code. Since then, I have dedicated myself to improving my skills and staying up to date with the latest trends and news in programming languages, tools, and technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, new blog!</title>
      <link>https://douglastofoli.dev/posts/hello-new-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 17:57:02 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://douglastofoli.dev/posts/hello-new-blog/</guid>
      <description>Happy new year! 🎉</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
